In this video we will run through our Gnome's Well development
First we will test the game and
We will play Gnome's well using our mobile phone.
Now where on the Main menu of the game, let's start by pressing new game.
As you can see the game is hard, and the Gnome dies when it hits a trap
For winning simulation we will make the Gnome invisible so we can demonstrate it without consuming more time.
Now, we will go to the architecture and main components of the game.
we will focus to our hierarchy pane.
Let's see first the Main Menu scene
take a look the hierarchy pane.
Here we have the menu scene
Main camera for this scene
Canvas where the image and button stored
MainMenu
and the Event System
Now let's take a look on Main Scene
Here we have the MainScene
Main Camera
Rope
Input Manager
Canvas
EventSystem
Game Manager
Start point
TreasurePresent
Background
Level
Rope hightlights
Our First coding will be the rope script where the rope physics happen
let's open the rope script by clicking the rope script
from the scripts folder in asset
This is our code for the rope
We will see a public class for the rope and declare the ropeSegmentPrefab to use
Here we will see the code for extending and retracting the rope
In start function we will cache the linereder and
we will call the ResetLength function
This is the ResetLength function
In CreateRopeSegments, this is where the rope segments created when we extend our rope
Next is the RemoveRopeSegment, called when rope is retracting
Next is the Update, it update every frame when
the rope is extending or retracting
this is the condition if we extend the rope
this is the condition if the rope retracts
Another highlights of coding is the bodypart
Let's see what it does
Here we have the code for the damage type when gnome hits trap
Slicing and Burning
Next is the DestroyGame function where when the gnome receive
damage it will end the game
UI, this is our main menu
It has the new game button to start the game
Next is the actual game UI
First we have the invicible checkbox at the upper left of the screen
to make the gnome invincible from the traps
at the upper right of the screen we can find the pause button
to pause the game and contains resume and new game button
at the lower right corner of the screen we can find the
up and down button to control the rope
So we're here at the project files directory
Let's take a look around on the asset folder
Gnome, Level, Scenes, Scripts, Sounds, and Sprites
this are the important components to build the game
Let's open the Gnome folder
Here we can find the prefabs and materials we use in developing the
game
next is Level
where all the level components like traps stored
Next is Scenes, where all scene of the game stored
Next is Scripts, where the script files of the game is stored
Next is Sounds, where all the sound effects used is stored
Next is Sprites, where all the sprites used is stored
Example is the parts of prototype Gnome we
assembled earlier is stored here
To build and run the game we will go to the file menu
and click build and run
It will ask to select a folder then after that click select folder
To run the game you will need to locate your build file
copy the apk file to your device and install it the it's ready to go
The only known issue we found is that the body parts of the Gnome
stays in the level even if the Gnome dies multiple times
Letting the Gnome's bodypart stay for couple of
seconds and vanish could be a possible improvements